<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jobs>
<job>
  <id>nhv-hoist-operator-pistoolhaven-nl</id>

  <title>Helicopter Hoist Operator – Offshore</title>

  <company>NHV Group</company>

  <category>Aircrew</category>

  <location>Pistoolhaven, Netherlands</location>

  <apply_link>https://nhv-group.jobtoolz.com/en/helicopter-hoist-operator</apply_link>

  <posting_date>2025-12-16</posting_date>

  <description><![CDATA[
MISSION: Offshore
AIRCRAFT:
SCHEDULE:
EMPLOYMENT TYPE: Full-Time
COMPENSATION: Competitive
IFR:
NVG:
LOCATION: Pistoolhaven, Netherlands

NHV in Pistoolhaven performs helicopter flights to transport ship pilots to ships off the coast of the Netherlands and Belgium.

The Helicopter Hoist Operator is responsible for the execution of hoist operations primarily in offshore missions. This position works closely with pilots, engineers, and other aircrew and reports to the Base Manager.

Responsibilities include:
- Coordinating passenger and aircraft handling procedures before and after flights
- Assisting with technical preparation of flights
- Conducting hoist operations in accordance with NHV procedures and the Flight Operations Manual
- Maintaining compliance with safety, quality, and operational standards

Requirements include:
- Helicopter technician background with hoisting experience preferred
- Minimum 2 years of relevant experience
- Medical Class 2
- English ICAO Level 4; Dutch required
]]></description>

</job>
<job>
  <id>apollo-medflight-hems-pilot-clarksdale-ms</id>

  <title>Helicopter Pilot – HEMS</title>

  <company>Apollo MedFlight</company>

  <category>Helicopter Pilot - HEMS</category>

  <location>Clarksdale, MS, United States</location>

  <apply_link>https://www.apollomedflightcareers.com/</apply_link>

  <posting_date>2025-12-16</posting_date>

  <description><![CDATA[
MISSION: HEMS
AIRCRAFT:
SCHEDULE: 14/14
EMPLOYMENT TYPE: Full-Time
COMPENSATION: $92,820/year + $10,000 local stipend + $46,000 retention bonus
IFR: Yes
NVG:
LOCATION: Clarksdale, MS, United States

Apollo MedFlight is seeking a Helicopter Pilot to support air medical operations in Clarksdale, Mississippi. Pilots work alongside medical professionals to provide rapid and critical care transport to patients in need.

Why Choose Apollo MedFlight:
- $46,000 retention bonus
- 14 on / 14 off schedule
- Company-paid travel to and from duty hitches
- Fully furnished on-duty and off-duty housing
- Strong focus on work-life balance and pilot support

Key Responsibilities:
- Retain final authority for the safe operation of the aircraft
- Ensure aircraft airworthiness and regulatory compliance
- Make operational decisions regarding flight acceptance and continuation
- Adhere to Crew Resource Management (CRM) principles
- Participate in Apollo’s Safety Management System
- Conduct pre-flight risk assessments and flight planning
- Ensure compliance with FARs, Operations Specifications, and company manuals
- Coordinate with maintenance and operational control as required

Requirements:
- FAA Commercial Rotorcraft–Helicopter with Instrument Rating
- FAA Second Class Medical Certificate
- Minimum 2,000 total flight hours (1,700 considered with approval)
- 1,200 helicopter hours
- 1,000 PIC hours
- 500 turbine hours (1,000 preferred)
- Night unaided/aided experience per company standards
- ATP and previous air medical experience preferred

Apollo MedFlight is an Equal Employment Opportunity employer and values diversity, inclusion, and professional excellence.
  ]]></description>
</job>

</jobs>
